# Dhruy Sharma

dhruv-sharma.com dhruvsharma0503@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/dhruvsharma78 github.com/dhruvsharma78

## **ABOUT**

I'm a Computer Science student at the University of California, Los Angeles (UCLA). I specialize in full stack web development, computer vision, image processing and text recognition and detection. I'm also interested in data science and analytics, with an emphasis on its use in the finance industry.

## **EDUCATION**

#### UNIVERSITY OF CALIFORNIA, LOS ANGELES - UCLA

Henry Samueli School of Engineering and Applied Science Computer Science

2018 - 2022 | Los Angeles, CA

Major GPA: 4.0 • Cum. GPA: 3.7

Completed Courses:

- Intro to CS
- Computer Architecture
- Software Construction

**Current Courses:** 

- Logic System Design
- Operating Systems
- Machine Learning (Stanford University, Online)

#### **GEMS MODERN ACADEMY**

High School

2014 - 2018 | Dubai, UAE

ISC: 94% • ICSE: 96%

Honors:

- KS Varkey Scholarship 2016 2018
- World Topper in Computer Science ICSE (2016) & ISC (2018)

## PROJECTS & ACTIVITIES

- Developed a library that provides tools to create a completely customizable dashboard display for vehicles. Currently in use by UCLA Formula Racing.
- Currently developing a stock market analysis tool that identifies historical and live patterns along with calculating multiple technical indicators to make predictions.
- Developing a website to allow users to view detailed stock information and news. My future plans for this website are to use my aforementioned stock analysis tools to publish insights and predictions that users can use.
- Member of UCLA Bruin Racing, UCLA ACM, UCLA Algorithmic Trading, and Bruin Trading.
- Completely self taught full stack web developer.

#### Check out my projects on my GitHub page (github.com/dhruvsharma78)

## **EXPERIENCE**

### DRUG DECIDER | UCLA DEVX

Full Stack Engineer

October 2019 - Present | Los Angeles, CA

• Developing DrugDecider (in partnership with the UCLA David Geffen School of Medicine), a health app that uses machine learning to predict a patient's treatment response to antipsychotic drugs.

#### **UCLA IT SERVICES | BRUIN ONLINE**

IT CONSULTANT

September 2019 - Present | Los Angeles, CA

• Provide primary support for clients at Bruin Online (BOL)

#### **BLUE DOME TECHNOLOGIES**

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING INTERN

July 2019 - September 2019 | San Francisco, CA

- Successfully researched and implemented methods to allow for accurate and fast text detection and recognition on images, dealing with issues like shadows, light, reflections, color, perspectives. Also added object tracking to supplement existing ML object detection models.
- Researched and implemented a service, from scratch, to stream video files to a server and process the video (using ML model) on the fly, thereby improving customer experience and wait times.

#### **BRUIN RACING**

FSAE ELECTRONICS & DATA ACQUISITION TEAM 2018 - Present | Los Angeles, CA

• Assisting in the design and implementation of electrical systems of the vehicle. Designed the dashboard on the car and currently developing a custom data logging system.

#### **ESRI**

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING INTERN August 2016 & July 2017 | UAE

- Created drivers to support to add support for new file types in ArcGIS.
- Used GDAL to create an automated testing script to test support for different image file types

## SKILLS

**LANGUAGES** C • C++ • Python • Java • JavaScript HTMI • CSS

**FRAMEWORKS** NodeJS • React • Express • Sass

**POPULAR LIBRARIES** Pandas • Matplotlib • Numpy Tesseract • OpenCV

**OTHERS** Microsoft Excel (Microsoft Certified Specialist) • SolidWorks • Adobe XD • Adobe Photoshop